- In a previous part of the course,
we showed you how to cancel
an active deployment,
rolling back to the previous
version of the application
that you had pushed.
In this section, we'll
look at rolling back
to a previous revision of your application
when there's no active
deployment actually running.
You can see the revisions available
for your application by
running `cf revisions`.
For my training app here,
you can see that I have three revisions.
There's one revision, number two,
where I've added a new
environment variable.
I can see that environment variable now
by running a `cf env`
and it's called `TRAINING_ENV_1`.
So if I wanted to roll back
to the revision before that, revision one,
I can do that with `cf rollback`
and specify version one of that revision.
You can go ahead and say 'yes'
and wait for Cloud Foundry to
roll back to that revision.
Once that roll back is complete,
I can look at the environment again
and see that that environment
variable is no longer there.
So rolling back to the previous revision,
the app code could have changed,
the droplet could have changed,
the environment could have changed,
just depends on what had happened
in those different revisions.
I can disable the ability
to roll back an application
by disabling the revisions
functionality for an application.
To do this, I'm going to need the app GUID
because I'm going to have to use `cf curl`
as there is no command in
the CLI currently to do so.
Once I have that GUID,
I can use `cf curl` to disable
the revisions functionality.
If I do that now,
I can still see revisions
for my application.
But when I go to attempt to rollback
to a different version of my application,
that will fail.
And of course, if I can disable it,
I can re-enable it
again by using `cf curl`
and now changing revisions
would be supported.