- As a developer, at some
point, you'll likely want
to connect to one of
your service instances
like a database, like our
training app database.
Perhaps to look at the table structure
or see what data's in there,
or verify a few things.
And it can be tempting
to just do a `cf env`
on our application and
use those credentials.
The problem with doing
that is that you end up
losing the audit trail and
it becomes difficult to
distinguish between what the
application did in the database
and what you potentially
did in the database.
And so it'd be better if we
actually had unique credentials,
one representing the service
binding of the application
which we already have, and
then two for us to connect
to our database and do the
things that we need to do.
In Cloud Foundry we can
do this relatively easily.
We can do that by creating a service key.
So we can do `cf create-service-key`,
the name of our service instance,
and then the name of
our service key itself.
So here I've given the
service key the name
of `psql-client`, because
that is a descriptive name
that denotes what I'm
going to use this key for.
I can then use `cf service-key` to
view the contents of that key.
And again, just a disclaimer
this service instance won't exist.
So the fact that these
credentials are recorded here,
is meaningless.
Once we have these
credentials, we can use them
and we can create a tunnel
through our application instance.
And the reason that we need to do this
in most Cloud Foundries, but not all,
is that most of the applications
the operators will have set up
a separate sub-net or network
and security rules around access
to those service instances.
And so we really need
to be an application or
within the application
network for the ability to
connect back to those service instances.
So we do that with an SSH tunnel.
In this first parameter that
we provide to `cf ssh` here
with the `-l` flag is the
port on our local machine.
This can be anything,
it's not uncommon to just
take the port of the
actual database, which
in our case here is 1433 and
throw a 6 in front of it.
This is our connection string, again
from the service key credentials above
and we're gonna create a tunnel
to our training application
and instance zero.
And so once we actually
get this prompt here,
we know that we actually
have a tunnel open
to that application instance.
So to use that tunnel,
we can open up another terminal window.
And in this terminal window,
we can use the `psql`
or Postgres client to
connect to our database now.
And you'll notice here
that in the `psql` string
the host is `localhost`,
and that's because we've opened a tunnel
on port 61433, all the way
through to our application
instance to the actual database.
And so that SSH tunnel is why
we're using localhost here.
And we can paste our password in
and now we're actually
connected to the database
and I can do whatever I need to.
In this case, there are
no tables in this database
but I can do the things that
I need to in that database.
I'm connected
through that application tunnel.
When I'm done with accessing the database,
I can go back to my
original terminal window.
I can exit out of the SSH tunnel,
and then I can restart the app instance
that I had tunneled to.
And this is a best practice
that we'll discuss more
in a future session.
And because we're done
with our service key,
we should go ahead and delete
it and just clean it up,
so that those credentials
aren't laying around.