- You can see the system
buildpacks configured
for your instance of Cloud Foundry
by running `cf buildpacks`.
These buildpacks are
maintained by operators
of your Cloud Foundry Instance,
and they'll be updated
by the operators of your Cloud
Foundry instance as well.
In the event though that,
let's say you needed
to use a specific version
of the staticfile buildpack,
one that is not built in
with the system buildpack
that you have here,
you can do that by specifying
the `-b` flag and the path
to the buildpack and the
tag of that buildpack,
in this case it's the
1.5.21 in a Git repository,
and if enabled on your
Cloud Foundry instance,
your Cloud Foundry instance
will go out to GitHub.
It will fetch this tag,
specifically this version
of that buildpack, and
it will use that version
of the buildpack to
create the container image
for your application.