- At some point you may need to access the
same managed service instance.
Maybe it's a database
or a message queue in
two different spaces.
Cloud Foundry will allow
you to share those service
instances across those spaces
provided that you have the
SpaceDeveloper role in both
of those spaces and provided
that this feature is enabled.
So I've got another
space called 'services'.
I'm going to go ahead and
use `cf shared-service`
and share my training app
database with that space.
If I do a `cf service` in
my currently targeted space
which is my dev space, I
can see that there's now
a section here called shared with spaces.
And I can see that it's shared
in my other services space.
I can target that services space.
I can run `cf service`
on the same database here
and see that, that
database instance is shared
across into this space.
So from here I could go ahead
and bind it into an application
in the services space
or do whatever I need to do with it.
Instead, I'm going to go back here
into my dev space and
I'm going to unshare it
because that's no longer necessary.
And in unsharing that database
I can do a `cf service`
again, back in my dev space.
And I can see that
it is no longer shared
with any other spaces.