- As a developer,
you'll probably want to check
logs for your applications
as you're doing development,
or troubleshooting issues.
There are two different
functions for logs built into the
CLI. The first is tailing logs.
We can do a `cf logs` and
the name of our application.
And this will tail logs in near real-time,
for the application, as
logs are being emitted.
So this command will
continuously run in the terminal
because it's basically
opening a websocket.
But we won't see anything here
because it's only streaming
logs in near real-time.
And so if nothing's happening
with our application
we actually have to go
generate some traffic
before we'll see logs.
So we can switch over to our app here.
I can refresh a few times,
generating some traffic
to our application.
And then when I switch back
I can see that the log messages
are actually showing up.
Now what you're actually seeing here are
log messages, not from
the application, but
from the Cloud Foundry routers
and that's coded with this `RTR` here.
If our application was logging
and writing its own log
messages to standard out or
standard error you would see those also.
But you see any log message
pertaining to traffic
getting to your application
or any log message pertaining
to the Cloud Foundry
components that are involved
in that process as well.
So in this case, we're actually
seeing the router logs.
Now to get out of this,
you can hit `control-c`.
If I just want to see logs
that have happened recently,
I can do `cf logs`, the name of my app
and then `--recent`.
And I'm seeing the same logs in this case.
But this is useful for
troubleshooting something that just
happened as an example,
or seeing what happened
in the past -
small amount of time.
Now be aware that this buffer is finite
both in space and time.
And so, your operators will
configure how many messages
each buffer for each
application can actually store.
Your operators can also
configure the amount
of time that those messages will be there.
And so they are not there permanently.
If you need a permanent log solution,
we referenced that in the
materials for the course.
The other thing that can
be useful is looking at
events for our application
so I can run `cf events`.
and you can see that I've
recently, not surprisingly,
because I just did the last exercise,
scaled the application,
and you can see that the
application was actually stopped
and started as part of that
secondary scale process.
But you see other events in here
like every time you
actually created an app
or did a push or updated an app.
Things like that show
up in the event queue.
So that can be useful as well.