- Let's take a look at the easy way
to create a manifest in
Cloud Foundry and that's to
allow Cloud Foundry to do it.
All we really need is
our running application
which we've already configured
in previous exercises.
And then we can run the `cf
create-app-manifest` command.
Cloud Foundry will look at the
config that we've already set
by the command line in
the previous exercise to
deploy this application.
And you'll see that we
now have a manifest file
in the directory that we
ran this command from.
We can take a look at
the manifest file and you
can see that Cloud Foundry
put in all of the information
that it knows based on
parameters that we passed
in previously.
It also added things that were default.
So in this case, the stack
and the health check type.
We'll talk more about what
these are later in the course.
We can test this and make
sure that our manifest works
by making sure that we're
in the right directory
deleting our existing
application, and then pushing
by using this manifest.
It's important that we
always test the manifest
that Cloud Foundry
generates, because now we
can open this application
in a browser and see
that things aren't working.
They are not working
for the same reason
they didn't work in the
source path exercise.
So if we go back
and look at the manifest again
you'll see that there's no path in here.
And the reason that there's no path is
that Cloud Foundry doesn't know where
on your local file system
you actually pushed from last time.
That's something it can't figure out.
And so what we can do
is one of two things.
You can add that to your manifest here
or you can simply push and
specify the path when you push.
And so in this case, I'm in
the appropriate directory.
I have app.zip, and I can
re-push. When I do this
and reopen the application
in a browser, everything will work.
The last thing to keep in
mind is that the precedents
between the command line and the manifest.
Anything you specify
on the command line will
override what's in the manifest.
And you can see that here
because we can do a push
and we can specify a larger disk size
in this case, 128 megs.
And you see
that when it actually
pushes the command line
value overwrites the value
that we have in the manifest.