- So far in this course,
we've used a single application domain
that's already been made available to us
in the Cloud Foundry
instance that we're using.
There may be other
domains available to you,
and you can see that by
running `cf domains`.
You can see that we have
the `cfapps` domain,
which I've been using.
There's also a `cert.cfapps` domain,
and a domain called `apps.internal`,
which we'll talk about in a later section.
But you can also bring your
own domains to Cloud Foundry.
So your company may have their own domain
that they want all of
their apps deployed on.
You can add your domain to Cloud Foundry
by running `cf create-private-domain`,
the name of the org
that you want the domain
to be available in, and
then the domain itself.
You'll note that a shared private domain
is initially scoped to an org,
but you can see by the message here
that you can share the domain
with other orgs if you need to.
Once you have that domain,
you can essentially create routes on it
and map routes to existing applications.
And so, I've used, now, that domain
to map to my existing
training application.
Now, it's important to note here
that just because I registered this domain
with my Cloud Foundry instance
doesn't mean it'll actually work.
And in fact, in this case, it won't work.
I will not be able to access my app
in a browser on this existing domain.
And the reason is that I
also need to configure DNS
so that the domain is resolvable,
and I need that DNS entries
for `my-domain.example.com`,
to map to the Cloud Foundry
instance that I'm using.
I also need to configure SSL certificates
somewhere with my Cloud Foundry provider,
and that varies by provider depending on
how they have their environments set up,
but we need to be able to
have valid certificates
for `my-domain.example.com` as well.
You can also delete private domains
and get rid of them and clean them up.
And when you do this, the existing routes
on that domain will also be deleted.