Before we get too far into the course,
let's deploy our first app.
If you logged out in the last exercise,
be sure that you're logged in again.
Remember that you can check
that with `cf target` and
make sure that you're logged in.
If not, log in however you choose.
We wanna make sure that
we're in the directory
where our application is.
So our first push application,
wherever you've downloaded
that on your machine,
make sure that you're in that directory.
If you look inside that directory,
you'll see our application along with
a file called manifest.yml.
This file contains some
directives for Cloud Foundry
on what to do with your application.
Let's take a quick look at that.
There's a few things that we specify here.
We name our application,
this is just the name
that we'll refer to it
in Cloud Foundry as.
We tell Cloud Foundry to
allocate 32 megs of memory,
64 megs of disk, and
create a single instance.
We're using this flag, random-route,
we'll talk more about that later,
but that's just to ensure we
don't have route collisions.
Our application is a regular
static file application and so we're using
a thing called the staticfile_buildpack.
Again, we'll cover all
of this in more detail
as the course progresses, but
we just wanted to give you
an experience of what
it's like to deploy an app
to Cloud Foundry.
So, provided we're in that directory where
the manifest exists, we
can simply type `cf push`.
The `push` command is what
you use to actually push
your application up to a
Cloud Foundry instance.
There's quite a few different flags,
and we'll use this command
again throughout the course,
but because we have our manifest file here
with the directives and the
minimum directives that we need
and we have our application
source in the same directory,
we can simply type `cf push`.
And when we do that, our
application gets uploaded
to Cloud Foundry.
We'll talk more about
what's happening here.
We get assigned to a particular route
where our application's running
and then it actually starts
our application and runs it.
You can open that URL in
a browser and you can see
that you now have an application running.
All you had to do, for all
intents and purposes, was assemble
a manifest file with a few
simple directives in it
and type `cf push`. Cloud
Foundry did the rest.