- The 12-factor app best practices
say to inject our configuration
through the environment.
This forces us as developers
to make sure that we separate
the things that can change
within our application
from the code itself.
We've provided a training app,
so we'll start by pushing
that application up.
You should know how to do this by now:
there's a manifest provided,
and the application is
provided as a zip file.
Just to make sure we can open
our application in a browser
and see that it's working.
We can then set environment
variables using `cf set-env`,
we'll go ahead and set three
environment variables right now.
This application is coded in a way
where it'll display environment variables
that start with the word TRAINING
in all upper case followed by an `_`.
And that's why we're using the convention
that we have here now,
but that is obviously not a
requirement of Cloud Foundry,
that's simply how the
application's written.
If we look at the
application now in a browser,
we don't see the
environment variables yet,
and that's because we need
to restart our application
for the new environment value
or values to be picked up.
So let's go ahead and
restart the application,
and then we can take a
look at the application
in a browser again.
Now you can see that the
training environment variables
again are shown here.
From the CLI you can also
inspect the environment
for any application that's running,
and you'll see that there's a
`User-Provided` section here.
Those are the values that we just set.
In addition, there's a
`System-Provided` section.
These are set by the
platform by Cloud Foundry
for every single
application: `VCAP_SERVICES`
we'll use later when we
actually bind services
to our applications,
and `VCAP_APPLICATION`
is set for every environment
and contains information
about the specific running application
and application instances.
If you go back to the application,
that's where we're getting things
like this app instance GUID from.
You can change environment variables
by using `cf set-env`.
Again, you'll have to
restart your application
for those changes to take effect.
Of course, if you're using a
manifest, and you should be,
you wanna make sure that
you add these values
to the manifest so that
they don't get lost
when you redeploy your application.
So the last thing to be aware of,
is that operators of your
Cloud Foundry platform
can set two different
`environment variable groups`
that would be made available
to every application
on the platform.
You may or may not have
these values actually set,
it depends on if they're configured
by your operators or not,
but in this case here,
you can see that on SAP,
they've made available
their CredHub service
and provided the API end
point for that service
via the running
environment variable group.
And in the staging
environment variable group
they haven't set anything.