- Okay, we are going to take a look
at the rolling deployment strategy.
We will look at it from
the context of a `cf push`
but just be aware that the
rolling strategy can be used
on restarts as well as restages.
So it will look pretty similar
to what you're going to see here.
I've already deployed the
application for the exercise,
the 'updating-app'. Up here in this window
in the upper right hand corner,
I'm running watch, so every half a second,
I'm essentially curling the application.
You can see the return
from the application
right now is 'BLUE'.
This is the first version
of the application.
In the window here on the bottom right,
I'm again, running watch.
And so every second I
am rerunning `cf app`
on the 'updating-app'.
Let's make a change to
the application over here.
We can change it from 'BLUE' to 'GREEN'
and then we can push.
This time we're going to do a `cf push`
except we're adding the `--strategy` flag
and the `rolling` strategy.
And so we can observe what happens here.
What you'll see in the
window on the upper right,
is that as the 'GREEN'
instances become available,
you'll start seeing 'BLUE'
and 'GREEN' in the response.
And what you'll see
down here in the window
in the bottom right,
is the new 'GREEN'
instances being scheduled.
You can see the first one
just showed up here and it's starting.
And what Cloud Foundry is
going to do is take one
of the 'BLUE' instances from
the top, it just did that,
start another one, and it'll
roll through that process,
grabbing an instance and replacing it
by starting a new 'GREEN' instance,
making sure that we have
some 'BLUE' and some 'GREEN'
and you can see in the upper right here.
Sometimes we're getting 'GREEN'.
Sometimes we're getting 'BLUE'.
Now we're over to a hundred percent green
and we've cut over our application.
We've made the change with zero downtime.
Great, so that's a lot
easier than the previous way
that we would do that.
If you're familiar with that,
it was called a blue-green deployment.
And essentially we would use
the `map-route` functionality
to add the route to two
different applications.
In this case, it's the same application,
it's built into the platform.
It's much easier.
It's more efficient.
Overall just a better solution.
So what happens though, now,
if we update our application again,
we deploy that application,
and we realize that something's wrong.
Well, we can also cancel
an active deployment.
As the deployment is running,
(and you saw that in the
bottom right corner here,
where it was rolling through taking
an instance of 'BLUE' out of service
as a new instance of
'GREEN' was put in service).
If something happened in that process
and maybe we just figured, you know,
there was a bug or a typo or
a test failed or something.
As we were updating to this next version,
we can cancel the deployment and see
what Cloud Foundry does.
So in order to denote that,
we'll change our application
now to display 'RED'.
And again, we'll do a
`push` except this time
I'm just going to use
the `--no-wait` flag.
And the reason I'm going
to do that is so that
I can cancel the deployment
in the same terminal window
instead of having four windows running.
So we'll see the same thing happen.
The 'RED' version is getting staged
and very shortly we'll start
seeing new 'RED' instances
being scheduled over here.
And we'll start seeing
'RED' being returned
in the upper right-hand corner.
What we want to do is
while this is happening,
we want to cancel the deployment.
So we've realized that 'RED'
is actually a bad version.
Excuse me, the
`cancel-deployment` command.
What you can see down here is very quickly
what Cloud Foundry did was
evacuate all of the instances
of 'RED' and immediately start
replacing them with 'GREEN'.
And so you can see that some of
those instances are still
starting. And up here,
you may have noticed that it
was possible to actually see
a little bit of downtime
during this process.
In accessing the application,
it could be possible to actually
not get a good working instance.
And that's because the goal
of canceling a deployment is
to as quickly as possible revert back
to the last known good state.
So in our case, 'GREEN'.
And so Cloud Foundry does that
by immediately shutting down
all of the 'RED' instances.
Now we still had some 'GREEN' running.
So there wasn't really
a big problem there.
But if we primarily had all
'RED' instances at that point
then we could have
experienced some downtime
or our users could've.