- We've provided another
sample application
to demonstrate the use
of multiple buildpacks.
This application uses two
languages, both Ruby and Go.
This application will
start a web server using Go
but will use Ruby to
process page requests.
So, that will require that
we have two buildpacks.
And just to refresh your memory,
you can see what buildpacks are available
by running `cf buildpacks`.
You can see the name
of the Ruby build pack
as well as the name of the Go build pack.
We'll need both.
When we push the application
it's no different than another application
except here we're specifying
that `-b` flag twice.
And here it's important to realize
that the order of these
buildpacks is important.
So, we put Ruby first and Go second.
And the reason that Go is last
is that the last buildpack
in the chain is responsible
for calculating that start command.
Now, remember in this application
it's going to start a Go web server.
And so we want to ensure
that the start command is
calculated by the Go buildpack
so that the web server starts.
Now, if we look down
here in the staging logs
we can see that at first,
the Ruby buildpack is being
applied and being processed.
And then second the Go
buildpack is being applied
and processed as well.
Once the push command is complete
we can run `cf app` on our app.
And you can see that both
buildpacks have been applied
and you can see the order that
they were applied in as well.
If we open our application in
a browser and all worked well
we should see a message
denoting essentially the
Ruby script was executed.
And again, this was served
by the Go build pack.
That's all for this exercise.
We can go ahead and delete
that application now.