- We have provided a sample application
written in Ruby that contains a sidecar
that's written in Go.
Let's start by taking
a look at the manifest.
Our sidecars are defined in
the 'sidecars' block here.
You can see that we have a single sidecard
named 'config-server'
and we've included
information on that sidecar.
For simplicity, we've included
the sidecar as a compiled
Go binary, but you could
use multiple buildpacks
if you wanted to.
Deploying this application is no different
than any other application.
It's just a `cf push`.
When the application's
done starting, you can see
that we now have our sidecar
`config-server` deployed
as part of the application.
Let's SSH into the application container
and take a look at the
processes that are running.
When we do a `ps aux`, you can see
that we have the
`config-server` process running.
We also have the `rackup` process running
which is the start command
specified for our application.
If we open the app in the browser and go
to the `/config` endpoint,
we'll see a response.
What happened here is the Ruby app
reached out to the sidecar
process and got some information
on some fake environment
variables and displayed that here.