- I'm going to demonstrate
the use of internal routes
by moving the training application
behind a new proxy
application that we'll deploy.
I'm going to start by running
`cf map-route` on the training
app and putting it on the
'apps.internal' domain.
Again, this is the internal domain
that's not routable from
outside of Cloud Foundry.
I can then go ahead and
remove the existing domain,
the domain that was routable
from outside of Cloud Foundry.
And so now my training
app is only accessible
on the 'apps.internal' domain.
I can see that by running `cf app`
and verifying the routes here.
So once I have that,
I'm going to deploy nginx
to serve as a proxy.
Now, this is just another
demonstration app.
This proxy isn't going to
do anything to our requests,
it's simply going to take
all requests coming to it
and forward those requests
to our training application.
You'll see that I deployed the proxy app
to that externally facing route.
This is the route that
the training app had
before I removed it.
If I run `cf apps`,
you'll see that I have two applications.
One is our nginx proxy and
again, this is the
externally routable URL.
The other is our `training-app`
only routable from
inside of Cloud Foundry.
When I open a browser now though,
requests to our nginx proxy fail.
And that's because the
proxy is not allowed to talk
to our training application.
In order to allow nginx to
talk to our training app,
we have to add a network policy.
We can do that with `cf
add-network-policy`.
And we specify the application
we expect traffic to be originating from.
In that case it's our proxy application
to the destination app.
In this case, our training application.
It will be communicating over HTTP.
So the protocol is 'tcp'
and the port is '8080', the default port.
If we do this and then we
wait about 20 to 30 seconds
for that change to propagate,
we can go back to our browser,
we can refresh the page
and it looks exactly like we're
accessing our training app.
Except our training app, in this case,
is now on that internal domain only.
Now this is a very simplistic example
because again nginx in this case,
isn't doing anything to our requests.
It's not actually providing
any additional security,
but we could, inside
of ningx configuration,
do IP filtering, creating
allow lists or denial lists,
we could implement authentication,
we could implement logging,
or other logic that nginx supports,
thereby protecting our backend application
(in this case, the training application).
Remember that on this network,
we explicitly have to allow traffic
from one application to another.
And so if we no longer
want the nginx proxy
to be able to access the training app,
we can simply remove that network policy
and we've disallowed that path
from the proxy to the training app.