- Up until this point
we've dealt with service instances
that you've provisioned
on demand, as needed,
brand new, from the marketplace.
But what if you had an existing
database that you wanted
to connect to or bind
to your applications?
Cloud Foundry has a concept called
User-Provided Services
which allows you to do this.
Essentially you are
providing the credentials for
that service instance, and
all of the information that
your application needs, manually using
the `cf
create-user-provided-service-instance`
command.
Now there's two ways to
create a service instance
or a user-provided service
instance, I should say.
One is the non-interactive way
where we're passing a
full on a JSON payload.
That's what I'm doing here.
The other is the interactive way.
Here, we're just passing in the names of
the keys that we want Cloud
Foundry to prompt us for.
I'll go ahead and specify some values.
The net result is exactly the same.
We end up with two service instances.
There is no way to distinguish whether
you created one interactively
or non interactively.
We want to illustrate the fact that
you could use both methodologies.
Now note, that the names non-interactive
and interactive are
actually really bad names
for a service instance.
So don't use something like that.
Use something more
descriptive like `hr-database`
or whatever it is that you're actually
creating the service instance for.
In this case we're just
using them as an example here
to demonstrate the two different ways
that we can create them.
So once we have them, they
are services instances.
We can just bind them to our application.
I can bind the non-interactive
to the training app as well as
the interactive to the training app.
Of course, I can also
inspect the environment here
and now I can see that
I actually have a new section called
user-provided under VCAP_SERVICES.
I have both of my service
instances represented there.
Of course, I need to restart
my application in order for
my application to be
able to see these changes
because it was a change to
our environment variable.
I'll go ahead and do that.
Now when I access my
application in a browser,
I can see that I have both
my user-provided services
as well as my training database
bound to my application.
You can also update a
user-provided service instance.
Note that when you're doing an update
you need to pass all of
the values back to the CLI.
The CLI is using a declarative
methodology here where you
need to say everything that
you want the state to be.
That means you can't just
update a single value
inside a user-provided instance.
You need to update all of those values
even if those values have not changed.
So I'll go ahead and
change those here again
using the interactive
way. I could have just
as easily done the non-interactive way to
update my user-provided service.
I can inspect the environment here
and the values for my
interactive service instance
have now been changed.
Of course, again, I have to
restart my training application
for the application to see it
because we've changed our
environment variables.