- So as a developer, you
will not have the ability
to maintain or change or
update security groups
within Cloud Foundry,
but it's important to
understand how to check them
and have awareness of what they are.
So security groups control
egress are essentially
where your applications can reach out to.
And operators can apply a default set
of staging security groups,
as well as running security groups.
After that, they can also
apply security groups
at the space level.
So let's take a look at
the staging security groups
that I have configured in
this Cloud Foundry instance
by the operators.
You can see that I have two:
one is called public
networks, one is called DNS.
For the running security groups,
I have the same public networks in DNS.
I also have a security
group called Containers
and another one called Hannah Trial.
We can look at any of these
individual security groups
by running CF Security
Group and the name of that.
And so I'm doing it
on the default DNS
security group that's here.
And what you'll see is
that my applications
with the DNS Security Group
are allowed to reach out
over the TCP protocol to any IP address
in this site or range and over port 53.
And so essentially going
out to make DNS queries.