- As you work more with Cloud Foundry,
at some point you'll
probably want to automate
some portions of your
workflow and your tasks.
And the Cloud Foundry API
can be used to do that.
Perhaps you're implementing
a CI/CD pipeline,
maybe you're generating
some kind of a report,
or maybe creating some
kind of batch process
for some of the elements within
your Cloud Foundry instance.
Anytime you need to parse the responses
coming from Cloud Foundry,
the API is the right choice for that
because the API returns
a content type of JSON,
which is easily parse-able by computers.
So let's take a look at the API here.
We will use a very simple example
and we'll just look at
the '/v3/apps' endpoint.
Essentially querying the API directly
for similar information
that would be displayed
if we did a `cf apps` directly in the CLI.
When you look at the
documentation for the API,
you'll notice that all
of the example requests
use `curl` directly.
Instead, we're going to
use the `cf curl` function
because that allows us to
skip setting the authorization
headers, the bearer token and
managing our authentication token.
It also allows us to skip
adding the API endpoint
to every single request.
So to invoke the `/v3/apps`
endpoint, as long
as we're authenticated, we
can do a `cf curl /v3/apps`.
And you'll see that we get
a response in JSON format.
Now, I only have one
application running here.
It is my training application.
You might have more at
this point in the course
depending on what you were
doing, but this should show,
in a paged fashion, all of
the apps that you have access
to within that Cloud Foundry instance.
And so this will show all of the apps
not just in your current space,
but in any spaces that you have a role in.
This is a simple request
to the `/v3/apps` endpoint
but typically we'll want
to parse those responses.
`jq` is a utility that we link
to in the course materials,
not related to Cloud Foundry,
but it is a JSON parsing utility
that is extremely helpful
in these cases.
So perhaps we want to, again,
curl the `/v3/apps` endpoint
but this time just extract the names
of all of our applications.
Well, if we're on a UNIX
system, we can again
curl the `/v3/apps` endpoint.
We can pipe it into `jq`
and we can extract the
appropriate value.
In our case, it is the name
field, and that will show us
the names of all of the apps.
This is a very simplistic look at curling
and interacting directly
with the API, but it's quite
powerful when you combine
the API with JSON parsing
and you can automate tasks
that you would normally
have to do manually. And you can do it
in a repeatable fashion because again
we're basically sending
and receiving JSON.
Formatted data, unlike in the
CLI where the output format
of any of those commands could change.
It would be a little bit risky to just
parse direct CLI output
commands in most cases.