- In Cloud Foundry, you can
have an app with no routes
or you can have an app with
a lot of different routes.
You can also have the same route
associated with multiple applications.
You can see what routes you already have
in your space by running `cf routes`.
You can see here that
I only have one route,
it's for my training app
and it's kind of messy, kind of ugly,
and that's primarily because
we use that `random-route` feature
when we first pushed the application.
So let's change it
to something a little bit more meaningful.
We can create a route in a space
by using `cf create-route`.
The first argument here is
the domain that we're going
to create the route on.
And then we can also optionally
specify the hostname.
In this case, I want
to use the same domain,
but change the hostname to
something more meaningful
in this case, `cff-training-app`.
You'll note that I can create
this route in this space
without actually having it
bound to the application.
I can associate a route
with the application
by running `cf map-route`.
And the command looks very similar
except we've added
the application that
we're referring to here.
So now when I look at my
training app, by doing `cf app`,
I can see that I have two
routes associated with it,
the old route and the new route.
Let's get rid of the old route,
because like I said, it's kind of ugly.
We can do that by un-mapping the route
from our application
with `cf unmap-route`.
Now, if I look at my training app again,
I can see that I have a single route,
just the one route that I want.
However, if I rerun `cf routes`,
I still have that old
route left in my space.
And I want to clean that
up because it's not in use
and I'm not going to use
it for anything else.
I can use `cf delete-route` to do that.