- So remember previously we had deployed
an application called `first-push`.
That application, that name, `first-push`,
is simply a human readable label.
Each of the resources
within a Cloud Foundry
installation will have
a globally unique identifier
or GUID assigned to it.
And so we can see that
GUID by doing `cf app`,
the name of the app,
and then `--guid`.
And this will be useful
when we start interacting
with the API a little bit,
but for now we just want to show you
that you can rename these resources
and that GUID won't change.
So there's a command called `cf rename`
and we give it the original name,
in our case `first-push`.
And then we give it a new name,
in our case `renamed-app`.
When we do this, the name changes,
but the GUID doesn't.
So if we actually rerun `cf app --guid`
we can see that it's exactly
the same GUID as it was before.
So again,
labels in Cloud Foundry
are there for human beings.
You can change those labels.
Labels are typically scoped to a space.
So you could have the exact same app
in a space for dev
and a space for test
and in a space for prod
with the exact same name.
So it's entirely up to
you how you use those.
From here on out,
we actually don't need this app anymore,
so we can go ahead and delete it.
We can do that with `cf delete`.
The `-r` flag will actually delete
the routes that are
associated with this app.
And so we can go ahead and do that
and say `yes`
and our application will be deleted
and we'll be ready to
continue with the course.