- I am going to demonstrate one
of the resiliency features
built into Cloud Foundry.
This is running for every
application within the platform.
In the upper right window here,
I am rerunning `cf app`
every half a second
on my training app and you can see
that I have five instances running here.
On the left window over
here, I'm tailing the logs
for my training app. And
in the bottom window here,
I'm going to invoke an endpoint
built into the training application
that programmatically
crashes an app instance.
What Cloud Foundry is doing
is monitoring the health of all
of my applications instances.
It knows that I want five running
and it will ensure that
five will continue to run
even when I programmatically
crash those instances.
We're going to `curl` the `/kill` endpoint
of my training application.
You can see that I get a
'502 Bad Gateway' error.
This is because the application fails to
return a response before crashing.
In the logs window here you
can see that very quickly
we've determined that the
application has crashed
and that the process has crashed.
You can see that it ended
up being app instance two
over here in this window.
You can see that that app
instance was very quickly
determined to be nonfunctioning,
essentially failing it's health check
and it was replaced by a new instance.