- So far in this course,
we've deployed applications
that had a single process.
But Cloud Foundry also
supports the ability
to push an application that
contains multiple processes
each running in their own container.
As an example, you might
have an application
that has a UI component,
which runs in its own process,
and a backend data component.
We've provided a sample
application called 'multi-process'.
You will see here that in the manifest
we've now defined two different
processes, web and worker.
We've defined the number of instances
and in this case, we've
provided the start commands.
Given that this is all the same codebase,
Cloud Foundry needs to know
how to start the different components.
Provided that we have that,
we can push our application
just like any other application.
And once the application starts,
you can see in the output
that we now have a web process
and a worker process.
You can see the same thing when
you run `cf app` on the app.
With multi-process apps,
we can scale each process individually.
In this case, we still use
the same `cf scale` command,
but this time we use the `--process` flag.
Now we've scaled our web
process to two instances.
We can then scale our
worker process to three.
If we want to SSH to an application now,
we again specify the `--process` flag
because there's multiple
processes for our application.
We can SSH to the multi-process app,
but to specifically the web process.
We don't actually need to do anything here
so I'm just going to exit out.
That's all we need this application for
so we can go ahead and delete it.