- The application SSH
feature can be disabled
for the entire Cloud Foundry instance,
at the space level, and
at the application level.
We can check if SSH is
enabled at our app level
by doing a `cf ssh-enabled`.
You can see that it is not
enabled for my 'training-app',
so I can go ahead and enable
it with `cf enable-ssh`.
I also need to check at the space level
and I can do a `cf space-ssh-allowed`.
You can see that SSH is not
allowed in my dev space.
So I need to go ahead and enable that
with `cf allow-space-ssh`.
Because I've made a
change to those settings,
I need to restart my application.
I'm gonna do it with the rolling strategy
to ensure that I have no downtime.
Once my application has restarted,
I can SSH to a particular app instance.
In this case, I'm going to instance zero.
And once I'm inside the container,
I can do a lot of things.
I can look around.
It may be helpful to take a
look at the 'app' directory.
That's where our application code exists.
The structure of that directory will vary
depending on the buildpack
that you're using.
More commonly you'll use `cf ssh`
to tunnel to a service
instance like a database.
We'll show you that in a future exercise.
I'm gonna go ahead and exit
out of the SSH session.
Then it's always best practice
to restart the application
instance that we SSH to.
And that's just in case we
accidentally made a change
or did something to corrupt
that particular instance.
I can do that with a `cf
restart-app-instance`.
This is why I SSH specifically
to the index of zero so
that I could only restart
the index of zero.