- We can use labels and annotations
to add more meta information
to our applications and other elements
within Cloud Foundry.
And this can be really
helpful for our own use
as well as to help out our teammates,
to build shared understanding
of what's happening
and what we've deployed and why.
So we can set labels on an
application with `cf set-label`.
In this case, we're setting it
on our app called training app.
We can then look at the
labels using `cf labels`
and the name of our app.
We can also use `cf apps --labels`,
and essentially use it as a search.
So we can look for all applications
that have the `env` equal to `dev`.
We'll go ahead and set another label here
and similarly, you can also
search for multiple things.
All labels that have `env` equal to `dev`
or `sensitive` equal to `true`.
Now we've done this on the command line,
of course it would be better
to do this in a manifest.
And so we'd want to add our labels
to our manifest and make
sure that they are persistent
and will be there when they re-push.
There are no commands in the CLI currently
to add annotations but
we can add annotations
in the metadata section of the manifest.
Maybe we want to do something like
add the contact person
for this application.
We can do that here.
Perhaps also we want our CI system maybe
to inject the version of the application
so that at any point in
time somebody could look
at the application and see what version
is deployed.