- Our training application is currently
using the `port` health check type.
And we can see that by running
`cf get-health-check` against
our training application
and we can see that
there's a single process,
and the health check type is `port`.
This is the default health
check for applications
and Cloud Foundry will connect
to the port of that application instance.
And if that connection
succeeds, it will assume
that the application
instance is alive and well.
That's fine for a lot of use cases,
but there are some cases
where perhaps your application
knows a little bit more about itself,
and whether or not it is
functional and working.
And in those cases, you can
define a health check endpoint.
An endpoint for Cloud Foundry to invoke,
which has the logic to
understand whether or not
that application instance,
is in fact, healthy.
We can do that with an HTTP health check.
We can change the health check type
for any of our applications.
In this case, Cloud Foundry
will make an HTTP call
to that endpoint and allow
the endpoint to determine
whether or not it's healthy.
If it returns a `200`
status then Cloud Foundry
will assume that it's healthy.
Anything else, it will
assume that it's not.
So we don't have an end point,
but we'll go ahead and do
a `cf set-health-check`
and change our health
check type to `http`.
Anytime you do this, you need to restart
your application for those
changes to take effect.
So we can go ahead and do that.
And then again, we can
fetch the health check type
for our training application
and you'll see that
we've changed it to an HTTP health check.
In this case, it's just
invoking the `/` endpoint
because we didn't specify one.