- Let's take a look at the marketplace.
This is where you can go as a developer
to provision services that your
applications need on demand.
We can look at what's available
in the marketplace by doing a
`cf m` or a `cf marketplace`.
This is going to vary depending
on the Cloud Foundry
instance that you're using.
All of the services
that you see listed here
have been configured in
this Cloud Foundry instance,
in this case it's SAP by the
SAP operators of this instance.
Your marketplace will likely vary
and differ depending on what services
the operators have made available to you.
Now, when we look through this list
it can be pretty significant
and you should certainly peruse
and see what's available to
you to provision on demand.
But let's just say for the
purposes of this exercise
I'm looking for a
Postgres or just some kind
of database service, because
there's so much in here.
Because I'm running on a Unix machine
I can use `grep` built
in utility from Unix
to look for a 'postgres' service
and basically just narrow it down
and find the thing that I want.
So in my case now there's a
service called `postgresql-db`.
That seems like that should work
for what we're trying to do here.
And so I can look at the details
of this particular service
by doing a `cf m` or a `cf
marketplace` with the `-e` flag
and the name of the service.
That shows me the description
of everything that's
available for me to provision
from this Postgres service.
In my case here in SAP there's
a single plan called 'trial'
it's free and I can see
some descriptions about it.
Let's go ahead and create
one of those services.
We can do that with `cf create-service`.
We give it the name of the service
in this case, it's called 'postgresql-db',
the name of the plan in this
case it's called 'trial',
and then the name of the service instance.
And so in my case, I'm going
to bind to this database
or make this database
available to the training app.
I want to give it a descriptive name
for me 'training-app-db'
seems to make a lot of sense.
As this is being
provisioned, you'll see that
the CLI has told us that
the create is in process.
The provisioning of these services
can either be synchronous or asynchronous.
In this case, it's asynchronous.
What that means is that I
need to periodically check
the status of the service
using either `cf service`
and the name of the
service or `cf services`
to see what the operation status is.
In my case here I can run `cf services`
and I can see that this service instance
is still being created.
While this is being created
it's important to realize
what's happening here.
So the marketplace is
an area where operators
have already said, "these
are things as a developer
you're allowed to provision and use"
(by the way provided that your
quota supports that, right,
because we've looked at quotas and limits)
"that we can provide there".
But assuming that we can, I as a developer
can get access to a brand
new postgres database
without opening a ticket,
without understanding
how to install postgres,
how to configure postgres.
All of these services that
are in this marketplace
are provided by a component
called a service broker.
A service broker is based
on the Open Service Broker API (OSBAPI).
This is a standard API
that allows any implementer
of a service broker to plug
in on-demand provisioning.
And all of the complexity
of that provisioning is hidden from me
because all I need to know
is a few simple commands:
how to look up the
services that are available
through the marketplace, how
to create service instances
and then what we're going to do next
how to bind and unbind
those service instances.
Some of these services
can take a little while to provision.
Some of the things might
be very, very quick -
it really depends.
Additionally, we only have a
single plan for postgres here
but there could be multiple plans.
You can think of plans as
kind of tiers of service.
Typically when you look at the plans
that are available you'll pick the one
based on the tier of service available.
It might be something
like a clustered postgres,
versus a single instance,
versus just a database
in a shared instance.
I only have access to this one trial plan
and that's because the
operators can control
what plans are available
in individual orgs
throughout the Cloud Foundry instance.
I can keep checking `cf services`
to check the last operation
for any asynchronous provisioning.
And when I can see that
create was successful
then I can proceed to
continue with the exercise.
Now we have this database
that's been created
all we needed to know again was
how to look it up in the marketplace
and how to run `cf create-service`.
Now, I want to tell my
application about it.
Doing that in Cloud Foundry
is called 'binding a service instance'.
We do a `cf bind-service`,
we provide the name of the app
that we want to bind it to,
and then the name of the service instance.
In this case, it's 'training-app'
and 'training-app-db'.
The process of binding essentially
has Cloud Foundry reach out
again to that service broker,
but this time to generate
unique credentials
in that service for our application.
So I do not need to know
how to go into postgres
and create and manage users.
All I need to know is
about `cf bind-service`.
And the configuration of how
my app needs to go connect
to that database is, not surprisingly,
injected through the environment.
We talked earlier in the environment
variables section about
this special system provided environment
variable called 'VCAP_SERVICES'.
'VCAP_SERVICES' is the
environment variable
where we will pass all of the information
that our application needs
to connect to this particular database.
Now, don't worry about
this actually being,
sharing passwords and names
and all of these things
on the screen here,
because the service
instance will be deleted
by the time you actually see this.
None of this sensitive
information will be relevant.
But what you can see
here is all of the same
standard information that we would need
to connect to a postgres database.
So things like the URL,
the name of the database
that was created, as
well as my credentials.
So my username, my password, etcetera.
All of that information is
injected through the environment.
Now, if I go back to my
application at this point
and I refresh I don't
actually see the database
connected here. That's because
we need to restart our application
just like we did in the
environment variable section.
Anytime we're changing the
configuration of our app
we need to do a `restart`.
So we can do a `cf restart`
on the training app.
Now when we access our
application in the browser
we can see that our database is bound
and our app knows about it.
Again this is a training app and
so it is coded to display
the bindings that it has.
But your application using this database
would use it just like any other database,
using the regular connection strings,
the database name, and the credentials.
Similar to binding, you can unbind
a service instance from an application.
The process of unbinding is essentially
removing those credentials
from the environment
and removing their
credentials from the database.
Now, if we look at the
`env` for our application
we can see that 'VCAP_SERVICES'
is in fact empty.
But if we go back to our application,
it still thinks it
knows about the bindings
simply because we have to
restart our application again
because the environment
variables have changed.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And we can go back to our
application now in a browser
and we see that service
instance is now gone.
Now it's important to
understand that in unbinding
it's ultimately up to the
authors of the service broker
in terms of what happens there.
In most cases, the
broker is going to delete
the credentials that it created
when we ran `cf bind-service`.
So those credentials
would be no longer valid
to access that particular
database instance.
That allows us to remove the binding
from our application, essentially
removing that service instance.
We can clean up that service
or get rid of that service instance
running `cf delete-service`,
and this will delete the database.
It will delete the service instance
by making a call to the broker.
Again, this can happen
synchronously or asynchronously.
In this case, it's
happening asynchronously.
You can see that delete is in progress,
but this will
delete the database and
remove it completely.