- When you go to work with
a Cloud Foundry instance
the first thing you need to
do is set the API endpoint
of the Cloud Foundry that you're using.
There's a couple
different ways to do this.
In this case, I'm just
using the `cf api` command
and using the URL of the API
endpoint of the Cloud Foundry
that I'm using.
Your API endpoint is probably
going to be different
than the one that I'm using.
I can also use the `cf api`
command to see which API
endpoint I'm currently targeted to.
This is useful if you frequently
interact with a lot of different
Cloud Foundry instances.
So once you've set that API endpoint,
the next thing you need to do is login.
I'll type `cf login --help`.
You'll note that one of
the things you can do
with the login command
is set the API endpoint.
And so you could use the `-a` flag
and skip the `cf api` command altogether.
You will also notice that
there's a few different ways
that you can log in to a
Cloud Foundry instance.
We'll cover a few of those
here, but not all of them.
The first way that I'm going to log in
is just interactively.
I'll just type `cf login`.
The nice part about this is
that your username and
your password don't show up
in your terminal history. And
you can see I'm now logged
in and I'm targeted to an org and space.
Another way to log in is
a browser-based login.
I can do that with a `cf login --sso`.
And this is typically the
one I use most frequently
because what this allows you
to do is use password managers
like 1Password or LastPass
that are integrated
with your browser and
authenticate that way.
So let me grab this URL
and open it in a browser.
When you do an SSO based login,
you get a temporary authentication code.
You then copy that authentication code
and paste that back in
your terminal window.
And you've authenticated
just the same way.
You can also use the
`cf target` command to
see which Cloud Foundry instance
you are currently targeted
and logged into.
The difference between
this `cf target` command
and the `cf api` command is this
also shows your org and space.
We'll talk about those a
little bit later in the course.
Logging in is important.
Logging out is also important.
So `cf logout` is the command to do that.
And if you rerun that `cf target` command,
you'll see that I'm no longer logged in.