- I'm going to execute
a sub-step deployment here
to demonstrate how it's used.
And you'll see that this
is far more complicated
than simply using `cf push`,
but there are certain
reasons that you may want
to interject things into
this sub-step process.
I'm gonna do this with my training app.
The most important thing
is to make sure if you
already have the training app
deployed, delete that first.
I don't.
I'm gonna start
by doing a `cf create-app`
and call it `training-app`.
This going to add some entries
into the cloud controller database.
I can see my app by doing
a `cf app`, and you can see
that I have some defaults
like the default memory usage
and not a lot of other information
because all Cloud Foundry
knows right now is
that my app is called 'training-app'.
Let's go ahead and apply the app manifest.
Once we do that and we
rerun `cf app`, we can see
that the manifest has been applied because
our memory usage has been
changed to match the manifest.
The next step is to upload our app bits.
For that we'll use `cf create-package`
and we'll specify the
path to our app bits.
We can see the packages available
for a given app by running `cf packages`.
Not surprisingly, I only have one
because I've only uploaded it once.
Next, we want to stage our application.
We can use `cf stage` and we
can pass in the package GUID
that was displayed when
we ran `cf packages`.
The output of the staging
process is a droplet.
I can see all of the droplets
for my application by
running `cf droplets`.
Again, I only have one
because I've only staged once.
Next, we want to use `cf set-droplet`
to specify the active droplet,
the one that we want Cloud Foundry to use
when we start our application.
Again, we referenced the GUID here.
And then we can start our application.
At this point, we have the same outcome
as if we had just typed `cf push`
but we did it with sub-step commands.