- You can see what users have roles
within an org by doing `cf org-users`.
In this case here, I'm the only user
and I have the OrgManager role.
Because I have the OrgManager role,
I could add users to roles
within my organization
with `cf set-org-role`
and I could remove users
with `cf unset-org-role`.
Similarly, I can see the
users assigned to my space
with `cf space-users`,
the name of the org,
and the name of the space.
In this case, again, I am the only user
and I have the SpaceDeveloper
and SpaceManager roles.
Because I have that SpaceManager role,
I could add users to my space
with `cf set-space-role`
and remove users with
`cf unset-space-role`.
Lastly, it's sometimes
useful to just get a list
of the unique users that
are assigned to a role
within the org or within
any spaces within the org.
And you can do that with `cf
org-users` and the `-a` flag,
of course, I'm the only
user within this org
and within any spaces within my org.