- The training application contains
a sample task that we can
run by running `cf run-task`.
And we provide it the
name of the application,
in our case, 'training-app'.
And then the allocations
of memory and disk applied
to the container running the
task, not to the application.
Remember, tasks run inside
their own containers.
We can name our task,
and then we can specify
what command we want to run;
what command the task actually represents.
In our case, we have simple
`sample-task.sh` script
in the 'tasks' directory
of the training app code.
We can check the status of our
tasks by running `cf tasks`.
And you can see that I've
run this multiple times.
You can see that the last run succeeded,
and all of our tasks, whether
they're simple or not,
will log to the same log stream.
So I can run `cf logs`
on my application again.
And I can see that my task logs
will be annotated with 'APP/TASK/`,
the name of the task,
and then the logs that are there.
So this is just a really simple example.
All it does is print a
statement in the log files.
Your tasks obviously would do
things that are more complex,
but they're very easy to work
with within Cloud Foundry.