You may have noticed previously
when we were running the `cf target`
or `cf t` command, that you
could see the org and space
that we were currently targeted to.
Orgs and spaces are logical separations
within a Cloud Foundry instance.
Orgs divide up a Cloud Foundry instance,
and spaces divide up each org.
Again, how you use these
is entirely up to you.
I can see the orgs that I have
access to by running `cf orgs`.
You'll notice that I
only have access to one.
This is not listing all
of the orgs that exist
in this Cloud Foundry,
it's just the orgs that I have access to.
And then I can see the
spaces within the org
that I'm currently targeted to,
which is my trial org here,
that I have access to, again
by running `cf spaces`.
And you can see that I
have two different spaces
that I have access to.
If I needed to change,
or set, my org and space,
the one that I'm currently working with,
that's just the `cf t`, or
`cf target` command, again.
You can pass the `-o`
flag for the organization,
and the `-s` flag for the space.
If you were just changing spaces,
so if I was just changing
to this test space,
I could just simply type `cf t -s test`,
and it would keep the same org.
You'll notice when we talk about labels
within Cloud Foundry and names,
that these orgs, these spaces,
they all have human readable names.
These are names that can
typically be changed depending on
if you have the right access control.
But these are just names
for humans to refer to.
And so if we go back to our
application that we pushed
in the first push exercise,
we gave that a name and
the name was, first-push.
This again is just the
human readable name.
There is actually a unique
identifier associated
with that application that exists
behind the scenes.
But this allows us to just do things like,
show the app details by
typing `cf app` and the name,
and not needing to know that unique,
very long string of characters
that make up the unique identification.
As we also said earlier, apps are always
scoped to a space or pushed to a space.
So you'll notice that this app exists
in a particular org in the dev space.
You cannot deploy an
application to an organization.
You're always deploying
applications to a space.