- As a developer, it's
important to understand
what quotas have been applied
to your orgs and spaces.
We won't do anything in this
course with setting quotas.
But we should be able
to observe them because
at some point if you use
Cloud Foundry long enough
you'll probably run up
against exhausting your quota.
So if we want to look
at our org, we can do
a `cf org` and the name of
the org, and then we can
look for the name of the quota.
So in this case, it's a
pretty long GUID here.
We can then do `cf
org-quota`, and the name
of that GUID to see the values
and what I'm allocated
across the entire org.
So every space within my org
will share four gigs of memory.
I'll have an eight gig instance limit
per instance, per app instance.
Obviously I can't use all
of that because I don't
even have eight gigs of
memory across my org.
I am limited to 10 routes,
400 service instances,
I'm allowed to generate paid services.
We'll talk more about that
coming up here in the class,
and I'm allowed 20 application instances.
I can do similar thing with the space.
I can do `cf space`.
I'm currently in my dev
space, and I can see
if there is a quota applied to my space.
You'll notice that there's always
a quota applied at the org level.
You may or may not have quotas
applied at the space level.