- Let's take a look at the difference
between restarting, restaging,
and repushing an application.
You've already restarted applications
quite a few times throughout the course.
When I do a cf restart
my existing application
instances, or container instances,
are destroyed and new
instances are rescheduled.
So we're not actually
restarting the same process,
the same container instance.
We are actually rescheduling
based on that container image
that we already have cached.
So this is the least destructive way
because we use the exact
same container image
or droplet that's already been created
and we just simply replace
the existing instances.
So when you're doing a restart,
you can restart all your app instances
and we'll look at rolling
restarts in the next section,
but you can also restart just
a single application instance.
This is actually
important to be able to do
for a variety of reasons.
But one of the most
common ones is if I SSH
to a specific app instance here,
I could potentially make changes,
whether I do that intentionally
or unintentionally,
to that running instance.
Now that running instance
is potentially different
than any of the other existing
instances that are running.
I can demonstrate that with
a pretty extreme example
by essentially deleting the app directory,
which is essentially where
our application code lives.
This running instance is
now quite corrupt, right?
I actually don't want that to be there.
The best practice is anytime I SSH
is to SSH to a specific instance.
And as soon as I'm done,
restart that specific instance,
I can do that with `cf
restart-app-instance`.
And as long as I pass
the same instance index,
in this case, zero, it will recreate
that instance which I had tainted.
So that brings us to restage.
So when we do a restage, this
is going to look an awful lot
like one of the first big
log blocks that come out
when we push an
application, because it is.
Essentially we're going through
that staging process again.
And so we're recreating that
droplet essentially using
the exact same app code
that's already cached.
In this case, the app code hasn't changed
but we're recreating the droplet.
You may need to restage anytime you think
the droplet could potentially change,
even if your application
code hasn't changed.
There are some agents that
work with different buildpacks
for things like application
performance monitoring
that can actually inject new things
into that runtime, changing the droplet,
in which case you need to do a restage.
More commonly, perhaps the buildpack
will be updated or the root file system,
called a stack, will be updated.
And so what we want to do is
do a restage in those cases
to pick up those changes.
Notice here, though, that
when you're restaging,
it's using the same application code.
So the application code hasn't changed.
We're recreating the container image
and then we're rescheduling
all of our app instances.
The last is re-push and in re-push here,
we'll do this in the next section,
but you're changing everything.
You're changing the application
instances or the, sorry,
the application code, you're changing.
Because the application
code changed, of course,
we're going through the staging process,
which is creating a new container image
and all of our existing
instances are also rescheduled.