- All right,
so here, we're gonna
look at some differences
between specifying a path
explicitly on a push and not,
and particularly we're gonna look
in the context of zip files.
So before you start this
make sure you're in the right directory.
Make sure you have the app.zip file
in the current directory
that you're working within.
Let's start by pushing this application
with the `-p` flag
and specifying our zip file.
And we'll take a look at what happens.
When we do this,
our app gets uploaded
and our app gets started.
We've got a URL here.
We can grab that URL and
open it in a browser.
And as expected Cloud Foundry
will take that zip file,
unzip it and run it as if it
was any other application.
So now let's take a look at what happens
when we push without the `-p` flag.
Remember that, we are in a
current directory with app.zip
so the same app.zip is
going to be uploaded.
Okay, so now when this application starts
and we open in a browser,
we get a 403 forbidden error from nginx.
But if we go back here and we actually
add `app.zip` to the path,
you'll see that we actually
download the zip file.
So there's two things
to keep in mind here.
One, when working with zip files
if you want Cloud Foundry
to unzip the artifact file
that you're pushing, you
have to specify the path.
Otherwise Cloud Foundry doesn't
know what to do with it.
We have this very valid use
case `zip-no-src-path` here
where we actually just want
that file to be served up
so that's what we're seeing
in their behavior here.
The second thing is it's always better
to get into the habit of
trying to specify the path
for all of the applications
that you're pushing.
We want repeatable deterministic behavior
and strange things can happen
if you inadvertently push
from the wrong directory.
So before we continue,
let's do a little bit of cleanup here.
We don't need the `zip-no-src-path`
application anymore
so let's just go ahead and delete it.
Remember the `-r` flag is
going to delete the routes
that are associated with it as well.
We will continue to use
the other application
the working application.
And so rather than delete it,
let's just go ahead and rename it.
So we rename it from
`zip-with-src-path` to `static app`.