You can check that you have the CLI installed correctly
and see what version you are running by typing `cf version`.
If you get an error when you do this, you should take a look
at your PATH variable and see what you have set.
Refer to the installation guide if you have any problems
and be sure you have the CLI installed correctly before proceeding.
It is also good practice to periodically check for updates
and install the latest.
The CLI is extensively self-documenting.
You can see the most commonly used commands by typing `cf help`.
You can see all of the commands the CLI supports by typing `cf help -a`.
You can see that this list is significantly longer.
You can see the usage details for any of the commands
by typing `cf  --help`
In this case, I have displayed the help text for the login command.
When you run `cf help`, you may notice that some of the
commands have shortcuts after them.
I have highlighted `cf marketplace` here,
and you can see you can type `cf marketplace`
or simply use the shortcut of `cf m`.
Not all commands have shortcuts,
but the ones that do are listed when you view the help text.
You can also change the language
that the CLI uses.
In this case I am using `cf config` to change the language to German.
When you run `cf help` again, you can see the descriptions
are now in German.
You will also notice the commands do not change
just the text around them and the descriptions.
You can turn this off by again using `cf config`
and clearing the locale.