- In Cloud Foundry, we
can scale applications up
or down in two different ways.
Horizontally scaling
is changing the number
of instances of the application running
and vertically scaling
is changing the resource
allocation allocated to
each container instance
running each of our application instances.
So let's look at horizontal scaling first.
I can do a `cf scale -i
2` for our training app
basically telling Cloud Foundry
that I want two instances
of the training app running.
In this case, we only
had one instance running
so Cloud Foundry started a second.
If we had too many instances running,
let's say we had four or five,
then Cloud Foundry would remove some
of the existing instances.
You can use the same
command to scale up or down.
Now, once this application
instance here passes a
health check Cloud Foundry will
start routing traffic to it.
We can see this by
going back to a browser,
going back to our training app,
and watching this app instance index here.
And if I keep refreshing, you can see that
I'm being load balanced across
both application instances.
So sometimes I'm getting
app instance index one
and sometimes I'm getting zero.
You'll note that I didn't
have to do anything
with load balancers or DNS
rules or anything like that,
Cloud Foundry basically
handled all of that for me.
When we go to vertically
scale an application,
we're actually changing the
resource allocations allocated
to each container instance
running each instance of our app.
So in this case we're
telling cloud Foundry
we'll want 48 megs of memory
and 256 megs of disk
for each instance.
You'll notice that the
CLI actually warns us
that this is going to cause
downtime in our application.
This is because Cloud Foundry has to
take those existing container instances,
destroy them and create new ones.
So let's go ahead and say `yes`, here.
You'll see that Cloud Foundry
stops our applications
and starts our instances back up.
And when those instances start back up
they have the correct
allocations of memory and disk.
You'll see here that
this instance actually
didn't report exactly
correctly just yet because
the command returned before
that instance was updated fully.
But if we rerun `cf app` on our app
we can see that now both
instances have 48 megs
of memory and 256 megs of disk.